Ashwani Kumar V

Senior Cloud Engineer

- **\(+91 7989 121 975**
- ✓ avardhineni7@gmail.com
- ♥ Hyderabad, IN
- in linkedin.com/in/avk-sd
- github.com/SimplifiedDevOps

SUMMARY

9.11 years of experience in IT field which includes 7+ years in handling AWS Cloud environments, Build and Administer Micro-Services architecture through Kubernetes and AWS EKS.

Proficiency in working in DevOps lifecycle management environment, creating build & release pipelines, Infrastructure Automation & Configuration Management in multiple environments.

Analytical, committed, persistent individual and reliable team member. Continuously learning and acquiring new knowledge and skills.

KEY SKILLS

Linux/UNIX Administration Bash Scripting, Python Scripting **Windows Server Operating Systems** AWS Cloud, Boto3 AWS Security, DevSecOps Terraform Ansible, Packer Git/Git Hub, Bitbucket, Maven, JFrog, Sonarqube Jenkins, CI/CD Integration Docker, Kubernetes, AWS EKS, Helm Charts, Prometheus & Grafana CloudWatch, IIRA

AWS Cloud Administration, Terraform, Ansible, Automation, Kubernetes Administrator with DevOps Lifecycle.

Professional Experience

Senior Cloud Engineer, Visionet Systems Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru Date: July 2021 – Till date

Job Profile: Build and Release Management, Deployment Automation, and Kubernetes Administration.

Cloud Engineer, TCS, Hyderabad

Payroll: Ivytel Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru,

Date: January 2018 - July 2021

Job Profile: AWS Administration & DevOps Engineer

Module Lead, Mindtree LTD. Hyderabad,
Date: February 2015 – December 2017
Job Profile: AWS Administration & Infrastructure Automation

Employment History

Roles and Responsibilities

- 1. Responsible for **fault-tolerance**, **high-availability**, **scalability**, **resilient** and **security** on AWS Infrastructure and platform.
- 2. Good understanding and implementation of **Microservices Concepts** and **Best Practices**.
- 3. Responsible for **Integration of CI/CD Pipelines** with automated build and test systems.
- 4. Responsible for **Production Deployment** using **Multiple Deployment** Strategies.
- 5. **Automating the AWS Infrastructure** and Platform Deployment with **Infrastructure as a Code Terraform**.
- 6. Build and maintain tools for **deployment**, **operations** and **monitoring**.
- 7. Support and **troubleshoot scalability**, **high availability**, performance, **monitoring**, **backup and restoration** of different environments.
- 8. Able to **carry out POCs** to make sure that suggested design technologies meet the requirements.
- 9. Evaluate **new tools, technologies** and processes to improve the speed, efficiency and **scalability of CI/CD environments**.
- 10. Used Jira as a Change Management, Work Management, Scrum Agile tool. Experience with the Project Management roles and terms such as Backlog, Epic, Stories, Tasks and Sprints.

Skills and Experience

- Expertise in deploying at scale, various Containerized web, data and service applications using Docker, Kubernetes, Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS), Elastic Container Services (ECS), CloudWatch, and other monitoring solutions.
- 2. Strong experience in **30+ AWS Cloud Native Services** in Compute, Storage, Database, IAM, Monitoring, Security vectors.

EDUCATION

Education History

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

- 3. Configured **AWS Security Services** such as IAM, KMS, ACM, WAF, Inspector, Trusted Advisor, AWS Config, Cloud Trail and Guard Duty to **secure resources** at multiple layers.
- Used **Terraform to build** instances and other AWS services into multiple environments such as Dev, Staging and Prod using AWS DevOps workflow.
- Standardized the Terraform modules for all the resources in AWS Cloud. This helped in reducing the code time and re-usability of the modules.
- 6. Automated the **creation of Golden AMI** through Packer and used **Ansible for Application Configuration.**
- 7. Extensively **used Ansible** to **install and configure** all the DevOps tools. Also **Dynamically configured the inventory file** to avoid manual input of IP address in the host file.
- 8. Used **Jenkins Pipelines** to integrate all Micro Services builds out to the Docker/ECR registry and then **deployed to Kubernetes/ECS/EKS**, and managed the application with various **Kubernetes Objects** also **integrated** with **Jira and Slack** to send build state information.
- 9. Optimize Jenkins container Configurations such as mount docker runtime inside container as a volume, fixing permissions on docker.sock, and scripted Jenkins configurations in to a Jenkinsfile to run Single Pipeline and MultiBranch Pipeline jobs.
- 10. Experience in administrating Kubernetes and a good understanding of manifest management with Helm along with expertise in Ingress Controller and Service mesh with Istio for Pod Communication and Encryption.
- 11. Used **Terraform to automate** the EKS Cluster and **integrated Terraform in CI/CD Pipelines** to automate provisioning of Servers.
- 12. **Automated tasks** such as System Checks, Adding Tags, Monitoring and Remote Administration, Backup and Restore, Scheduled tasks, Clean-up, Data Visualizations, Send Notifications, CI/CD related tasks **through Python Scripting**.
- 13. **Configured ELK/EFK ElasticStack** for deep search and data analytics, fluentD for centralized logging, log enrichment and parsing and Kibana for powerful and beautiful data visualizations.
- 14. Used **Jira as Change Management** and **Scrum Agile tool**. Worked on Scrum Sprint Activities and able to deliver within the sprint duration.
- 15. Configured Prometheus Server and its components such as Grafana, Alert Manager, ServiceMonitor, Prometheus Rules to monitor all Cluster Nodes, K8S Components, Microservices Applications and Redis Data broker.
- 16. Successfully upgraded the Kubernetes and Jenkins by following the best practices and effective took the backup of ETCD database and performed timely restore drills.
- 17. **Performed Cost Optimization** with Kubecost to avoid overspending on the resources.

Looking Forward To Learn

- 1. Azure Cloud, Azure DevOps
- 2. GCP
- 3. CKA, CKS Certification
- 4. New DevOps tools that emerge during my DevOps Engineer Journey.